# **POOJA KURBETTI**

# **QA** Manager

Contact:
+918951640176
pooja.kurbetti89@gmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/pooja-kurbetti-06042030/

QA Manager with comprehensive understanding of manual and automated testing techniques. Experienced in developing and implementing quality assurance processes to improve customer satisfaction. With overall experience of 12+ years leading cross-functional teams in software testing, defect tracking, and quality assurance. Proven record of meeting deadlines and improving overall efficiency.

# **Technical Skills**

#### Expertise in

- Programming languages: Java, Python, Groovy
- CI CD: Jenkins, Docker, Linux, Kubernetes, Kafka, Git, SQL
- Quality Assurance: Automated Testing, Functional Testing, Non Functional Testing
- Management: JIRA, HP ALM, Agile Methodologies

#### Certifications

- ISTQB Foundation Level Tester
- AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials
- Google Analytics Begineer

# **Professional Experience**

QA Manager at Kristal AI, Bengaluru

Tenure: November 2021 - Present

- Monitored and coordinated quality assurance activities to ensure that products are developed to meet customer requirements and industry standards.
- Designed and implemented automated testing frameworks for web-based and mobile applications.
- Established and maintained metrics to measure product quality and customer satisfaction.
- Utilized various automation tools to streamline the software development process and improve the quality of the final product.
- Implemented a continuous integration pipeline to improve the quality of software releases.
- Oversaw teams of up to 15 people responsible for ensuring the quality of the product.
- Performed Performance Review Cycles and constant feedback sessions with the team members
- Recruited, trained and managed a team of highly skilled IT professionals.

# SDET Lead at Halodoc, Bengaluru

Tenure:May 2020 - November 2021

- Developed and implemented automation solutions for various software applications to increase system efficiency and accuracy.
- Utilized various automation tools such as Selenium, Cucumber and REST Assured for automated testing.
- Participated in creating and executing test plans, test scenarios and test cases.
- Performed root cause analysis to identify the underlying issue in the automation process and resolve the same.
- Created detailed bug reports and communicated them to the development team.
- Implemented strategies to ensure the stability and scalability of automated tests.
- Collaborated with development teams to analyze and optimize code for better performance.
- Led a team of 10 SDETs cross-functional teams to enhance the frameworks as OKRs

QA Lead at Amadeus, Bengaluru

Tenure: July 2015 - May 2020

- Led a team of 10+ Quality Assurance Analysts in the development, implementation and ongoing maintenance of quality assurance processes.
- Developed and implemented performance metrics to monitor the success of quality assurance activities.
- Proactively identified and communicated issues and risks in order to improve processes and ensure quality service delivery.
- Actively sought out and developed new methods and techniques to improve the effectiveness and efficiency of the quality assurance process.
- Developed and implemented a comprehensive QA training program for new employees.
- Developed and maintained comprehensive test plans and test cases to ensure quality of product.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure quality of product development and delivery.
- Collaborated with onsite teams and developed a training plan to support shift left approach.

Senior Quality Engineer at Manhattan

Associates, Bengaluru

Tenure:October 2013 - July 2015

- Developed and implemented test plans and test scripts for manual and automated testing of software applications.
- Conducted compatibility and regression tests to ensure software applications were functioning properly.
- Monitored and tracked bugs and defects, and documented results in defect tracking systems.
- Participated in peer reviews to ensure quality assurance standards were met.
- Developed and maintained automated test scripts using scripting languages.
- Developed and maintained accurate and up-to-date testing documentation.

Senior Test Engineer at Mindtree Ltd, Bengaluru

Tenure: August 2011 - October 2013

- Developed and maintained automated test scripts for functional and performance tests.
- Monitored test execution and reported results to stakeholders and leadership.
- Generated comprehensive test reports that provided visibility into the product quality.
- Created and maintained test data to support testing activities.
- Developed manual test cases to ensure complete coverage of all functional areas.
- Utilized bug tracking software to log and track defects.
- Developed and implemented automated smoke tests that quickly identified production issues and allowed for rapid resolution

# **EDUCATION**

Year of Graduation:

August 2007 - July 2011

University:

KLESCET Belgaum (VTU), Belgaum

Majors:

Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical &

Electronics

Graduated with 65%

# Languages Known

English - Proficient Hindi - Proficient Marathi - Proficient Kannada - Proficient